She got nothing short of an ass-blasting,
我們玩了各種花樣，
I can tell you that much.
我只能告訴你那麼多
Bitch had a foot fetish or something,
那賤人有戀足癖還是什麼的，
I don't even know.
我也不懂
I'm Andrew Neyman.
我是安德魯奈曼
Tune the set to B-flat and
先調到B調，
then you'll turn my pages during rehearsal.
等一下你先在旁邊幫我翻頁
Excuse me?
不好意思?
Could I have a B-flat please?
可以幫忙我調一下B調嗎?
Could I maybe have --?
或許能幫忙我調一下..?
Milk the cunt!
幹他媽的快調音!
Down the line.
按順序吹
We have a squeaker today, people.
我們今天有菜鳥，各位
Neiman. Nineteen years old.
奈曼，19歲，
Isn't he cute?
他是不是很可愛?
Nei-man ...
奈曼...
Alright, gang.
好啦，小夥子們
'' Whiplash ''
"揮鞭猛擊"
Page.
翻頁
Page!
翻頁了!
Stop. Barker --
停，巴爾克..
That is not your boyfriend's dick.
那不是你男朋友的小弟弟，
Do not come early.
不要急著來
Skipping ahead.
繼續演奏
Bar 93.
93小節
Five-six-and
5、6、接著來..
Stop!
停!
Now this one really upsets me.
現在真的讓我不開心了，
We have an out-of-tune player.
我們有個吹得亂七八糟的團員
Before I go any further would that player
在我說出來前，
care to identify himself?
有人願意自首嗎?
Maybe a bug flew in my ear.
也許是有蟲飛進我的耳朵
Bar 115. Five-six-and --
第115小節，5、6、接著來..
No.
不
No, my ears are fine,
不，我的耳朵好得很，
we most definitely have an out-of-tune player.
絕對有人在亂吹
Whoever it is this is your last chance.
不管是誰，這是你最後的機會
Either you know you are playing out of tune
無論你是知道你吹錯
and are therefore deliberately sabotaging my band,
並且因此壞了我的樂團
or you do not know you're playing out of tune,
還是你不知道吹得不對
which I'm afraid is even worse.
比起來這應該是更糟糕
Reeds.Five-six-and --
看譜，5、6、接著來..
Bones.Five-six-and --
長號，5、6、接著來..
Ah, he's here.
噢，找到了
Tell me it's not you Elmer Fudd.
告訴我不是你吧，艾默佛德
It's ok. Play.
沒關係，繼續
Stop.
停
Do you think you're out of tune?
你知道你吹錯了嗎?
What are you --
你是怎樣..
there's no fucking Mars bar down there.
地上並沒有士力架好嘛
I'm up here, look at me.
我就在這裡，看著我
Do you think you're out of tune?
你知道你在亂吹嗎?
Yes.
知道
Then why the fuck didn't you say so ?!?
那你為什麼幹他媽的不應話?!?
Jesus !!
我的天啊!!
I have been carrying your fat ass for too long, Metz.
我已經容忍你的肥屁股在這裡太久了，梅茲
I will not let you cost this band a competition
我不會讓樂團因為你而失去獲勝的機會
because you can't keep your mind off
因為你滿腦子都是快樂兒童餐
a fucking Happy Meal and on pitch.
而沒辦法專心在音準上
Stein -- congratulations,
史丹..恭喜了
you are no longer alternate,
你不再是儲備樂手，
you are now fourth chair trombone.
現在你是第四長號手
梅茲..給我該死的滾出去
Metz -- get the fuck out.
For the record, Metz was not out of tune.
回到剛剛的弦律，梅茲沒有吹錯
You were, Wallach.
你才吹錯了，瓦拉赫
But he didn't know.
但他分不出來
And that's bad enough.
那就夠糟糕了
Alright, take ten.
好吧，休息十分鐘，
When we get back, the squeaker is on.
等會兒回來，新人就得加入了
You know if Fudd put half the effort
你知道如果佛德分出
into playing the trombone
他對垃圾食物一半的熱忱
as he does into polishing off
來練習長號像他喜歡秒殺的
cheeseburgers, we wouldn't be....
那些漢堡一樣，我們才不會....
Listen, Andrew.
聽著，安德魯
I know what you saw in there is worrying you.
我知道你在那裏頭看見的事嚇到你了
But there's a big difference.
This is your first day.
這是你的第一天
Metz had been dragging mud for two years.
梅茲已經擺爛兩年了
Besides,you're no Elmer Fudd.
而且，你不是艾默佛德
This is a huge opportunity for you--
這對你來說是個很大的機會..
you know that, right?
你知道的，對吧?
Yeah ...
我知道...
Your parents musicians?
你的父母是音樂家嗎?
No -- not really ...
不...不算是...
What do they do?
他們在做什麼的?
Well my dad is a writer --
嗯，我爸是個作家..
Oh. What's he written?
喔，他寫過哪些作品?
Well -- I guess he's mainly a
嗯..我想他主要從事..
he's a teacher, mainly, I guess.
他是個老師，主要是老師，我猜啦
College?
哪一間學校?
Pennington High.
賓尼頓高中
What about your mom, what does she do?
那你媽呢,她在做甚麼的?
I don't know.
我不知道
She left when I was a baby.
我還是嬰兒時她就離開我了
So no players in the family?
所以你家族裡沒有玩音樂的?
No, I guess not ...
不，我想沒有...
Well, you just have to listen to the greats then.
嗯，你只能向偉大的音樂家學習了
Buddy Rich, Jo Jones.
巴迪瑞奇，喬瓊斯
You know, Charlie Parker became Bird
你知道，查理派克就是叫做"鳥"的那個樂手
because Jones threw a cymbal at his head.
因為瓊斯朝他的頭丟了個鈸
He cried himself to sleep that night
那夜他哭著睡著，
but it made him Bird.
但從此也轉變為所皆知的人物
You see what I'm saying?
你懂我的意思嗎?
The key is -- just relax.
重點是..放輕鬆
Ok?
好嗎?
Don't worry about the numbers or what the other players think.
別擔心韻律還是其他樂手怎麼看
You're here for a reason.
你能在這裡是有原因的
You believe that, right?
你相信我說的，對吧?
Yeah.
是的
Say it.
照著說一遍
I'm here for a reason.
我能在這裡是有原因的
Yeah.
是啊
Ok?
可以嗎?
Alright. Now have fun.
好啦，現在玩開心點
Alright, gang. "Whiplash".
好了，小夥子們，"揮鞭猛擊"
Neiman -- just do your best. Ok?
奈曼..盡力做到最好，好嗎?
Five-six-seven
5、6、7..
Let's hear some fills.
我們來聽些好聽的
We've got Buddy Rich here!
我們有個巴迪瑞奇在這裡!
Ok --- little trouble there, no problem.
好吧..有個小問題，不要緊
Let's pick it up at 17.
回到第17小節
接著..5、6、7..
Not my tempo. Ok?
節奏不對，好嗎?
Five-six-seven
5、6、7..
Downbeat on 18. Ok?
強拍落在第18小節，可以嗎?
Five-six-seven
5、6、7..
The and of 4 ---
4個拍子..
bar 17,the and of 4. Ok?
第17小節，4個節拍，好嗎?
And ... five-six-seven
接著..5、6、7..
17, the and of 4. Ok?
第17小節，4個拍子,可以嗎?
And you're rushing a little.
你有點搶拍了
Alright? Five-six-seven
好了嗎? 5、6、7..
Not quite my tempo.
這和我的節奏不一樣
All good, here we go.
太好了，我們繼續
No --- ready?
不...預備起?
Five-six-seven
5、6、7...
Sorry, you're dragging a little now.
抱歉，你現在拖拍了
Here we go.
繼續
All set? Five-six-seven
都好了? 5、6、7..
You're rushing.
你又搶拍
Five-six-seven
5、6、7..
Dragging.
現在又拖拍
Five-six-seven
5、6、7..
Why do you suppose I just hurled
為什麼你讓我想向
a chair at your head, Neiman?
你丟張椅子，奈曼?
- I don't know.  - Yes you do.
- 我不知道  - 你知道
Were you rushing, or were you dragging?
你幹什麼不是搶拍就是拖拍?
I don't know.
我不知道
Start counting.
算拍子
Five-six-seven
5、6、7..
In four, damnit!
4個拍子，白癡!
One-two-three-four--Look at me.
1、2、3、4..眼睛看我
One-two-three-four --One-two-three-four
1、2、3、4..1、2、3、4..
one-two-three-four
1、2、3、4..
Stop. Was I rushing or was I dragging?
停，我有搶拍或拖拍嗎?
Rushing or dragging?
搶拍或拖拍?
I don't know.
我不知道
Start counting again.
再算一次拍子
One-two-three-four ---
1、2、3、4....
one-two-three-four ---
one-two-three-four
1、2、3、4....
Stop. Rushing or dragging?
停，搶拍或拖拍?
Rushing!
搶拍了!
So you do know the difference!
那你知道不一樣在哪裡了
If you deliberately sabotage my band
如果你故意要破壞我的樂團
I will fuck you like a pig.
我會像幹譙豬一樣幹譙你
Now are you a rusher or are you a dragger
現在你是趕時間還是拖拖拉拉?
or are you going to be on my fucking time?!?
還是你要跟著我該死的節奏?!?
I'm going to be on your time.
我會跟好你的節奏
What does this say?
這是什麼?
A quarter-note 104.
104小節上的一個四分之一音符
Give me a 104.
打104小節的拍子給我聽
One-two-three-four----
1、2、3、4....
one-two-three-four---
one-two-three
1、2、3、
Jesus fucking Christ,
我操他媽的老天爺，
I did not know they allowed retards into Shaffer!
我真不敢相信他們讓智障加入Shaffer!
Am I to believe
我可以相信
that you cannot fucking read tempo?
你天殺的就是弄不懂節奏嗎?
Can you even read music??
你懂什麼音樂??
What the fuck is this?
這幹他媽的是什麼?
- It's a half-note. - What is this?
- 這是二分之一音符  - 這是什麼?
It's a dotted sixteenth.
這是第16個打擊點
Sight-read this measure.
讀清楚這一段
Bop-bop-ba-bop-ba-bop-ba-bop
What are you, in a fucking a cappella group?
你在做什麼，你是該死的人聲樂團嗎?
Play the goddamn set!
打好天殺的節奏
Stop.
停
Now answer my question.
現在回答我的問題
Were you rushing or were you dragging?
你在搶拍還是拖拍?
Answer me !!!
回答我!!!
Rushing.
搶拍
Look at me.
看著我
Dear God, is that a tear?
親愛的上帝，那是眼淚嗎?
Are you one of those single-tear people?
你是那些愛哭鬼其中之一嗎?
Do I look like a double fucking rainbow to you?
你是看到彩虹了嘛？你有必要這麼感動嘛
How fucking upset are you right now?
你現在有多該死的沮喪啊?
I'm not upset.
我沒有沮喪
Oh, so you don't give a shit about any of this?
噢，所以你對這一切都不屑一顧囉?
I do give a shit
我沒有不屑..
So you are upset or are you not ----
所以你是非常沮喪還是不是....
yes or fucking no?
是還是該死的不是?
I am ---- yes.
我....是的
- You are upset.  - Yes I am
- 你很沮喪   - 是的...
- I am   - Say it
- 我是..  - 說啊..
I am upset.
我很沮喪
Say it so the whole band can hear you.
說大聲點讓所有團員都能聽清楚
Say it so the whole fucking band can hear you!
再說大聲點讓大家都幹他媽的聽清楚啊!
I am upset!
我很沮喪!
- I am upset!  - Louder!
- 我很沮喪!  -大聲點!
- I am upset!!  - Louder!
- 我很沮喪!!  - 再大聲點!
You are a dickless, friendless, worthless
你這個沒種、沒朋友、沒價值、
faggot-lipped fucking piece of shit,
同性戀的該死的窩囊廢
whose Mommy ran out on Daddy
難怪你媽要離開你老爸
because she found out he wasn’t Eugene O'Neil,
因為她發現他才不是尤金歐尼爾
and who is now weeping
而且現在是誰在擦眼淚還留了
and slobbering all over my drum kit.
我整組鼓上都是口水
So for the last father-fucking time
所以為了最後的他媽的父親時間
say it louder !!!
說大聲一點!!!
I am upset !!!!!!
我很沮喪!!!!!!
Carl ...
卡爾...
Start practicing harder, Neiman.
再練得更努力點，奈曼
Alright gang ---
好了小夥子們...
"Whiplash" , bar 115 to the end.
"揮鞭猛擊"，演奏第115小節至結束
Five-six-and
5、6、接著來...